# Ravindra Nagaraja

Vice President - India Talent Acquisition Operations - at Accenture

## Summary

In my 16+ years of core Operations and Service Delivery experience, I have managed services for clients across industry - Communications, Technology, Products, Resources and Financial Services. I have successfully led call center providing technical support to global consumers of the worlds largest technology company. I have setup and grown learning operations shared service center in India and other geographies to provide end to end learning services.

In the past 7+yrs I have been actively engaged in supporting pre sales, sales and solution effort towards pursuing new opportunities. I have successfully built the Learning Administration capability and won two large client engagements recently.

Core Expertise: Operations Management, Client Relationship Management, Business Development, Transitions Management, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Assurance, Cost Management, Business Solution and Contract Management.

## Experience

#### Vice President - India Talent Acquisition Shared Services at Accenture

April 2016 - Present (1 year)

In my current role as Talent Acquisition Shared Services Lead, I am responsible to keep the Candidate Sourcing and Supply engine running across different channel sources and ensure fulfillment of business hiring demand as per the commitment. Ongoing collaboration with the Talent Strategy, Business and Vendors to understand and deliver to the business need, attract and source right talent across different skill sets and capabilities.

Resume Screening, Interview Scheduling, Document Collection and Document Audit, Database Updates, Background Check completion for all candidates joining Accenture India across growth platforms and operating groups.

Leveraging new generation talent acquisition tools and technologies is my primary focus, and deliver quality of service at the lowest cost per hire is one of the goals.

#### **Vice President - Client Relationship Lead at Accenture**

May 2015 - April 2016 (1 year)

In my current role as Client Relationship Lead role for one of the largest technology client, I am accountable for maintaining strong client relationship by consistently delivering contractually agreed deliverable and providing value added services. I am responsible for account financials, sales and grow the services.

### Vice President - Global Service Delivery Lead at Accenture

September 2013 - June 2015 (1 year 10 months)

In my current role as VP - Global Service Delivery Lead, I am responsible for delivering Learning Services under Talent Management capability to our clients across geographies. Over all 450+ employees supporting learning services across different geographies in more than 30 languages.

Operations Management, People and Performance Management, Client Relationship, Cost Management, Budgeting, Contract Renewals, Sales and Solution support are other key responsibilities.

#### GM - Learning Service Delivery and Training Administration at Accenture

March 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 6 months)

In my current capacity as GM - Learning Delivery and Training Administration services, I am leading End to End learning services for Fortune 500 clients out of 3 delivery centers in APAC. Managing Learning as a business towards meeting clients organization needs and supporting them to achieve their learning vision by training their employees across skill, capability and professional behaviour development areas by leveraging ILT and vILT modes of training delivery. Training delivery and operations has grown tremendously in the last 5yrs and technology has played a key role in taking Training Delivery Methodology to a new level.

I am currently leading approximately 250+ people across India, China and Philippines supporting more than 10 global fortune 500 clients.

#### Manager - Learning Scheduling & Administration at Accenture India Services

June 2007 - February 2010 (2 years 9 months)

I manage service delivery for 8 clients globally under learning shared service model. I am responsible for managing onshore and offshore teams.

#### **Manager Operations at Convergys**

April 2003 - January 2007 (3 years 10 months)

Convergys India Services was one of the fastest growing BPO / ITES companies in 2002 / 2003 which primarily focused on voice support for its clients customers.

I was one of the first employees who was hired for a Technical Voice Support deals in 2003, where I was involved in all stages of the transition to go live. I was responsible for delivering the Tier 1 and Tier 2 SLA's for the clients EMEA and NA business. We grew from a team of 35 FTE's to 150 FTE's providing end to end (voice, chat, email) support to our clients customers.

I was responsible for:

- 1) Managing a team of more than 150 Technical Support professionals
- 2) Managing client relationship from the Operation Delivery perspective
- 3) MIS (Reporting, Validation and Analysis)

This was one of the most stable deals we still have in Convergys and by Jan 2007 we had grown to a team of 300+ FTE's and Convergys was the largest vendor for this client handling 70% of the clients calls across all its vendors.

### Team Lead - Operations at e4e Inc (Formerly known as iSeva Systems)

November 2001 - April 2003 (1 year 6 months)

iSeva Systems Pvt Ltd was one of the first 3 BPO companies to start in Bangalore. I joined the company as a Customer Care Executive and with in a year I grew to a Team Lead role managing a team of 10 - 15 executives.

I gained knowledge and experience of managing:

- 1) Out Bound Calling / Sales Team
- 2) Email and Chat Teams
- 3) Inbound Voice Customer Service

#### Programmer at Infoniche Technologies Pvt Ltd

January 2000 - October 2001 (1 year 10 months)

Creating WBT/CBT for some of the clients from School/Universities.

#### Courses

### **B** Sc, Computer Science

K L E College, Bangalore University

Computer Science

## Skills & Expertise

**Team Management** 

**Order Management** 

**Transition Management** 

**Process Improvement** 

**CRM** 

**Call Center** 

Management

**Contract Negotiation** 

Six Sigma

**Change Management** 

**Service Delivery** 

**BPO** 

**Analysis** 

**Business Strategy** 

**Business Analysis** 

**Business Development** 

Leadership

**Business Process Improvement** 

**Project Management** 

**Performance Management** 

**Program Management** 

**Training** 

**Vendor Management** 

ITIL

**Operations Management** 

**Customer Relationship Management (CRM)** 

**Outsourcing** 

**Business Process Outsourcing (BPO)** 

**Call Centers** 

**IT Service Management** 

**Quality Assurance** 

**Contact Centers** 

### Education

### K L E College, Bangalore University

B Sc, Computer Science, 1997 - 2000

Activities and Societies: National Institue of Information Technology (NIIT) - Completed GNIIT certification (1998 - 2000)

#### K.L.E. College, Bangalore University

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Computer Science, 1997 - 2000

Activities and Societies: Joint Secretary for the Annual collect Fest "Sanskar - 2000"

#### **Interests**

Automobiles, Engineering Innovations, Sales and Marketing, Operations Management, Client Relationship, Business Strategies, Project Management, Travelling and Sports

## Languages

## **English**

# Ravindra Nagaraja

Vice President - India Talent Acquisition Operations - at Accenture



## 1 person has recommended Ravindra

"I have known Ravi for a while now and when we first met he was a Team Leader at convergys. I took over that business when it was in total mess and my first reaction was how come this business is still held together. But when I met Ravindra I got my answer. Against all odds this young team leader along with his few other colleagues were managing the show, holding it together. Within a very short time, with minimum guidance Ravindra along with his other team leader colleagues turned around the business. From nothing going right they made it one of the most admired business unit to be a part of. In the process they also taught me a lot. Ravindra is extremely hands-on, focused, always willing to learn, high on integrity and very knowledgeable. If given an opportunity I would like to have him on my team any time. He would be an asset always in any situation and for any business."

— **Mahesh Punia**, managed Ravindra at Convergys

Contact Ravindra on LinkedIn